so now that we have seen what ilp is and
also how it relates to ipc we can have a
little discussion about the lp and the
ipc
we have defined our ilp as basically the
ipc on an ideal out of order processor
that has perfect branch friction enough
resources for everything etc and we saw
that ilp is larger than or equal to the
ipc that can be achieved on any real
processor so if we consider a narrow
issuing order processor narrow issue
meaning that it can only issue about
maybe one two maybe three instructions
per cycle and it's in order
usually the limitation for the ipc will
be this basically the in order property
is not going to hurt us too much
so this processor is going to be limited
mostly by the narrow issue
however if we have a wide issue in order
processor meaning it can do more
instructions per cycle
it's going to be limited mostly by
the inorder property because this is
going to allow it to do a lot of
instructions per cycle and if it can do
closely to what the ilp already is for
the application then basically we're
already kind of close to ideal as far as
the ipc
is concerned for for the wide issue
problem but because of the inorder
property we just cannot find those
instructions to keep our wide issue
slots busy so if we have a wide issue
processor we also need for it to be out
of order so that it can benefit from the
wider issue by finding instructions
anywhere where they are and not
basically stopping on the first
dependence
so such a processor will need to fetch
execute etc more than one instruction
per cycle preferably a lot more than one
so it cannot be just like two it should
be four maybe or more
that's why we call it wide issue
it should be able to eliminate false
dependencies between because if we have
to obey all sorts of dependencies then
that's going to limit our ipc2
and bring us far away from the ideal ilp
and finally should be able to reorder
instructions so that we can execute
instructions out of order meaning that
our execution order should be kind of
similar to what we did for the ilp and
not
for what we did for the in-order
processors